Before connecting the LoRaWAN server to our IoT platform.
We need to understand who is going to be the subscriber, the publisher, and the broker.
Actually, it's not that straightforward because there are two possibilities.
So we'll see both of them on this figure.
I represent at the top the LoRaWAN server and at the bottom the IoTplatform.
Most of the time the LoRaWAN server exposes by default a MQTT broker.
So we don't need to configure anything and the broker is already available and enabled.
If you want to use it,
so if a publisher on the subscriber wants to connect to this broker, then we just need to check the
credentials and the topic hierarchy of this broker.
Everything is in the documentation of each LoRaWAN server and that is definitely the easiest way to
proceed.
So in that case, who is the subscriber and who is the publisher?
For both its the IoT platform.
The subscriber on the IoT platform is going to check its favorite topic on the broker, usually the uplink
stream, and the publisher is going to send messages to the broker, usually messages for the device,
so the downlink stream.
The nice thing with this architecture is that we don't need to set up an MQTT broker, but only two
clients, one subscriber and one publisher.
We'll make a demonstration for this architecture.
But before I would like to present you a second architecture that you might find.